{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"blood acidity is reduced by excessive breathing.",
					"slow, shallow breathing eliminates too much carbon dioxide.",
					"the level of carbon dioxide in the blood increases.",
					"dangerous acids accumulate in the bloodstream."
				],
				"question": "Alkalosis is a condition that occurs when:",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "blood acidity is reduced by excessive breathing."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Trachea",
					"Alveoli",
					"Bronchi",
					"Capillaries"
				],
				"question": "In what area of the lungs does respiration occur?",
				"source": "See Anatomy of the Respiratory System"
			},
			"back": "Alveoli"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"a complete cessation of respiratory effort.",
					"labored breathing with reduced tidal volume.",
					"shortness of breath or difficulty breathing.",
					"a marked increase in the exhalation phase."
				],
				"question": "Dyspnea is MOST accurately defined as:",
				"source": "See Introduction"
			},
			"back": "shortness of breath or difficulty breathing."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"there must be low quantities of pulmonary surfactant to allow for full alveolar expansion.",
					"the percentage of inhaled carbon dioxide must exceed the percentage of inhaled oxygen.",
					"oxygen and carbon dioxide must be able to freely diffuse across the alveolar–capillary membrane.",
					"the pulmonary capillaries must be completely constricted and the alveoli must be collapsed."
				],
				"question": "In order for efficient pulmonary gas exchange to occur:",
				"source": "See Physiology of Respiration"
			},
			"back": "oxygen and carbon dioxide must be able to freely diffuse across the alveolar–capillary membrane."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the brain stem inhibits respirations.",
					"respirations decrease in rate and depth.",
					"respirations increase in rate and depth.",
					"exhalation lasts longer than inhalation."
				],
				"question": "When the level of arterial carbon dioxide rises above normal:",
				"source": "See Physiology of Respiration"
			},
			"back": "respirations increase in rate and depth."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"The pulse oximeter is a valuable assessment tool that measures the percentage of red blood cells that contain hemoglobin molecules.",
					"Most otherwise healthy patients can maintain adequate oxygenation and good skin color with oxygen saturation readings as low as 70% to 80%.",
					"Caution must be exercised when using the pulse oximeter on a patient with carbon monoxide poisoning because falsely low readings are common.",
					"Pulse oximetry measures the percentage of hemoglobin that is saturated with oxygen but does not measure the actual hemoglobin content of the blood."
				],
				"question": "Which of the following statements regarding pulse oximetry is correct?",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "Pulse oximetry measures the percentage of hemoglobin that is saturated with oxygen but does not measure the actual hemoglobin content of the blood."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"place her in a recumbent position to facilitate breathing.",
					"determine if she has been prescribed a beta-agonist inhaler.",
					"call medical control and ask how to proceed with treatment.",
					"contact medical control and administer an antihistamine."
				],
				"question": "A conscious and alert 29-year-old female with a history of asthma complains of difficulty breathing that began after her morning jog. The temperature outside is 40°F (5°C). On exam, you hear bilateral expiratory wheezing. After providing supplemental oxygen, you should:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "determine if she has been prescribed a beta-agonist inhaler."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"start at the lower lung fields and determine at which level you start hearing clear breath sounds.",
					"pay special attention to the exhalation phase because this is when you will likely hear rales or rhonchi.",
					"note the presence of a high-pitched whistling sound, which is an indicator of fluid in the lungs.",
					"auscultate the posterior chest first and compare the apex of one lung to the base of the opposite lung."
				],
				"question": "When assessing for fluid collection in the lungs during auscultation of lung sounds, you should:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "start at the lower lung fields and determine at which level you start hearing clear breath sounds."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"diffuse collapsing of the alveoli.",
					"a unilaterally collapsed lung.",
					"a bacterial infection of the lung tissue.",
					"fluid accumulation outside the lung."
				],
				"question": "A pleural effusion is MOST accurately defined as:",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "fluid accumulation outside the lung."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"inspiration and expiration.",
					"oxygenation and ventilation.",
					"diffusion and oxygenation.",
					"ventilation and diffusion."
				],
				"question": "The two processes that occur during respiration are:",
				"source": "See Physiology of Respiration"
			},
			"back": "inspiration and expiration."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"respiratory system.",
					"cardiovascular system.",
					"endocrine system.",
					"immune system."
				],
				"question": "Asthma is caused by a response of the:",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "immune system."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"normal breath sounds.",
					"abnormal breath sounds.",
					"an absence of breath sounds.",
					"diminished breath sounds."
				],
				"question": "When auscultating the lungs of a patient with respiratory distress, you hear adventitious sounds. This means that the patient has:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "abnormal breath sounds."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"stridor.",
					"rales.",
					"rhonchi.",
					"wheezing."
				],
				"question": "Harsh, high-pitched inspiratory sounds are characteristic of:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "stridor."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"30 breaths/min with supraclavicular retractions and clammy skin",
					"22 breaths/min with an irregular pattern of breathing and cyanosis",
					"20 breaths/min with shallow movement of the chest wall and pallor",
					"24 breaths/min with bilaterally equal breath sounds and pink skin"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following is MOST characteristic of adequate breathing?",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "24 breaths/min with bilaterally equal breath sounds and pink skin"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"a narcotic overdose.",
					"an overdose of aspirin.",
					"high blood glucose levels.",
					"a respiratory infection."
				],
				"question": "Hyperventilation could be associated with all of the following, EXCEPT:",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "a narcotic overdose."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"unilateral paralysis and slurred speech.",
					"anxiety, dizziness, and severe bradypnea.",
					"tachypnea and tingling in the extremities.",
					"altered mental status and bradycardia."
				],
				"question": "Common signs and symptoms of acute hyperventilation syndrome include:",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "tachypnea and tingling in the extremities."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Narcotic overdose",
					"Pulmonary edema",
					"Severe anxiety",
					"Pleural effusion"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following conditions would be LEAST likely to result in hypoxia?",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "Severe anxiety"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"respiratory difficulty.",
					"adequate air exchange.",
					"respiratory insufficiency.",
					"an obstructed airway."
				],
				"question": "An alert patient presents with a regular pattern of inhalation and exhalation and breath sounds that are clear and equal on both sides of the chest. These findings are consistent with:",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "adequate air exchange."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"expiratory wheezing.",
					"profound cyanosis.",
					"rales and rhonchi.",
					"audible stridor."
				],
				"question": "At the onset of an acute asthma attack, patients commonly experience difficulty breathing and:",
				"source": "See Causes of Dyspnea"
			},
			"back": "audible stridor."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-16-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Alupent.",
					"Singulair.",
					"Ventolin.",
					"Atrovent."
				],
				"question": "Albuterol is a generic name for:",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care"
			},
			"back": "Ventolin."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-16",
		"label": "Chapter 16"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}